<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Barry's Site</title><link>https://shvier.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Barry's Site</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 14:21:29 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shvier.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ZK Hack IV Puzzle 3: Chaos Theory</title><link>https://shvier.github.io/posts/2024/0201/zk-hack-iv-puzzle-3-chaos-theory/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 14:21:29 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://shvier.github.io/posts/2024/0201/zk-hack-iv-puzzle-3-chaos-theory/</guid><description> Bob designed a new one time scheme, that&amp;rsquo;s based on the tried and true method of encrypt + sign. He combined ElGamal encryption with BLS signatures in a clever way, such that you use pairings to verify the encrypted message was not tampered with. Alice, then, figured out a way to reveal the plaintexts&amp;hellip;
Puzzle Explanation The Solution</description></item><item><title>ZK Hack IV Puzzle 2: Supervillain</title><link>https://shvier.github.io/posts/2024/0131/zk-hack-iv-puzzle-2-supervillain/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 14:41:24 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://shvier.github.io/posts/2024/0131/zk-hack-iv-puzzle-2-supervillain/</guid><description>Bob has been designing a new optimized signature scheme for his L1 based on BLS signatures. Specifically, he wanted to be able to use the most efficient form of BLS signature aggregation, where you just add the signatures together rather than having to delinearize them. In order to do that, he designed a proof-of-possession scheme based on the B-KEA assumption he found in the the Sapling security analysis paper by Mary Maller 1.</description></item><item><title>ZK Hack IV Puzzle 1: Gamma Ray</title><link>https://shvier.github.io/posts/2024/0130/zk-hack-iv-puzzle-1-gamma-ray/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 14:43:31 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://shvier.github.io/posts/2024/0130/zk-hack-iv-puzzle-1-gamma-ray/</guid><description>Bob was deeply inspired by the Zcash design 1 for private transactions and had some pretty cool ideas on how to adapt it for his requirements. He was also inspired by the Mina design for the lightest blockchain and wanted to combine the two. In order to achieve that, Bob used the MNT6753 cycle of curves to enable efficient infinite recursion, and used elliptic curve public keys to authorize spends.</description></item><item><title>Proof of Liability with zk-SNARKs, Re-explained</title><link>https://shvier.github.io/posts/2023/0718/proof-of-solvency-with-zk-snark/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 17:01:02 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://shvier.github.io/posts/2023/0718/proof-of-solvency-with-zk-snark/</guid><description>This is a re-exposition of Vitalik&amp;rsquo;s customized IOP about proof of solvency. The protocol was intuitive when I first read it, so I didn&amp;rsquo;t think about the details thoroughly. When I was designing a protocol of proof of solvency, I wanted to compare the pros and cons of the existing designs. So this post came out.
KZG commitment KZG is one of the most prevalent polynomial commitments. It is widely used in generating proof of zero knowledge.</description></item><item><title>Prerequisites for Zero-Knowledge Proof</title><link>https://shvier.github.io/posts/2023/0227/prerequisites-for-zkp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 16:49:24 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://shvier.github.io/posts/2023/0227/prerequisites-for-zkp/</guid><description>Preface I started my research on ZKP last month. There were many unfamiliar math concepts for me, such as group, order, elliptic curve, etc. After struggling for several days and with the help of my professor, I understood them gradually. Now I want to construct my knowledge base in this field. My best bet is to rephrase these contents like executing rubber duck debugging. This is why I decided to write a series of articles to help me review the ideas.</description></item></channel></rss>